♪ ♪
♪ Motherless children
has a hard time ♪
♪ When Mother's gone ♪
♪ Motherless children
has a hard time ♪
♪ When Mother's gone ♪
♪ They don't have
no food to eat ♪
♪ Sometimes no
shoes on their feet ♪
♪ Motherless children
has a hard time ♪
♪ When Mother's gone ♪
♪ Nobody will treat
you like Mother did ♪
♪ When Mother's gone ♪
♪ Nobody will treat
you like Mother did ♪
♪ When Mother's gone ♪
♪ Friends will do
the best they can ♪
♪ Till your friends
don't understand ♪
♪ Motherless children
sees a hard time ♪
♪ When Mother's gone. ♪
Yes!
Yeah... get it.
Thank you.
That was terrific.
Thank you! That was...
That was really great.
Thank you. Do I know you?
Not likely, my man.
Well, you play
a hell of a guitar.
Hey, thanks. You play?
No, no, no, no, not like that.
You're Eddie Cougar
Haynes, aren't you?
You recorded a couple
albums in the-the late '50s.
Played all the jazz
clubs in the '60s,
and-and you disappeared
in the early '70s.
Man, it's good
somebody remembers.
Yeah, well, grab your
gear, I'll stake you to a meal.
Yeah?
Absolutely.
All right. You got it.
All right, I'll grab
your bag here.
Hey, hey, hey. Oh,
this is a pleasure.
Let's go! All right.
Whoo!
Man! Is this yours?
Oh, yeah.
What'd you do, rob a bank?
Something like that.
Ever hear of Dreams?
Dreams?
No, I don't think so.
Ah, it's my band.
Yeah, it's how I got all this.
We were together
about eight years.
Made ten albums...
Seven platinum, two gold.
Ooh!
A lot of fun while it lasted.
Boy... now I
produce a little and,
you know, write a few songs.
I bet you do.
Come on. Let's go.
Terry, you're late.
I did the grocery
shopping for you.
Eddie, this is my mother.
Lorraine Maslin, Eddie Haynes.
How do you do?
Eddie's one of the
world's greatest blues
guitarists. How nice.
Don't forget...
Your uncle's coming to
my house for dinner tonight.
I'll bring him over
here about 9:00.
Fine.
Oh, Terry.
The band's waiting
for you by the pool.
Thanks for the shopping, Mom.
Hey look, man,
maybe I better go.
No, no, no. Forget it.
Come on. Come on in.
Here we go.
My, my!
Let me grab your
guitar from you there.
Look at this!
Whoo!
Yeah. Hey.
Wow!
You been living here long?
Oh, yeah, I was... I
was born in this town.
Yeah, about five years
ago I decided to stay.
So I went out and I...
I bought the biggest
and best house I could find.
I like what you've done with it.
Thank you.
Yeah, it's-it's interesting.
Yeah. You hungry?
I could eat
something. All right.
All right, let's get
some food here.
Here. Ooh!
Look at this.
All right!
Look, um, help yourself.
If you feel like cooking
anything, go right ahead.
I gotta go talk
to the band here.
Shouldn't take too long.
Ooh.
Thanks, Terry.
Hey just... What? What?
End of conversation, guys.
I don't want to talk
about it. Terry...
Look, just... would
you just leave, all right?
All right!
Who's that?
A friend of mine.
Come on. Let's go.
See you, Terry.
Could you use a drink? I could.
Anytime, man. All right.
Sorry about that.
Well... what's your
pleasure, my friend?
Oh, a little rye
would be all right.
A little rye would be all right.
We can do a little rye here.
Straight up for me.
Straight up for you? Yeah.
All right, I'll match you.
There we are.
All right.
Well... Here's to it.
Mmm.
You know, I'm gonna
write you a song.
Ah. I'm gonna put
your name on it.
That way, if it's a hit,
you can live off the royalties.
For a while, anyway.
Come on now.
It can't be that easy.
Well, people like me got
rich ripping off people like you.
It's payback time,
my friend. All right with me.
♪ ♪
Hello.
Hi.
I'm gonna be working
here a couple of hours.
No problem.
Nice!
Yeah!
Yeah, yeah. You know,
you're welcome to stay, Eddie.
No.
Your mother's coming back,
and I don't want to
cause no problems.
No, forget about that.
Look, I'll be back in
the morning, okay?
All right, where
you gonna sleep?
Well, there's a big
oak tree in the park
I sleep under and
it's real comfortable.
All right.
Can I take you
there, at least? No.
I'll be back for
breakfast in the morning.
How's that? All right.
Breakfast is around noon.
Okay.
Thanks for everything, yeah?
Good night, Eddie. Bye-bye.
Bye.
Good night, Eddie!
Night!
You coming in?
Uh, you go ahead.
I'll be in in a minute.
All right.
♪ ♪
There he is!
Hands against the tree!
Come on. Up! Up!
Hands against the tree! What?!
What's going on?!
Spread your feet.
Well, well.
Look what we have here.
Yeah.
Ben.
Dan Guerney.
Sorry to call you so early.
I wanted to catch you
before you left for the office.
You did a good job, Dan.
Ben... Ben?
What?
Got a murder out here.
Thought it might interest you.
Dan, I... I got all the
work I can handle in town.
I think the DA's
got the wrong man.
Ever hear of Eddie Haynes?
Are you talking about
Eddie "Cougar" Haynes?
♪ ♪
Hello, Eddie, I'm Ben Matlock.
Oh, the sheriff's friend.
I like your music.
I heard you once
in a club in Atlanta.
That must have
been The Lion's Head.
I always played The
Lion's Head in Atlanta.
Yeah, that was a long time ago.
Yeah.
20 years, maybe more.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Eddie, uh, how'd you
wind up on the streets?
Not taking care of business.
Drinking too much,
partying too much.
Anything else?
Well, I did time...
Three to five for assault
on some club owner
that stiffed me for my pay.
When I come out, most
of the clubs were gone,
and the ones that was
left... They wouldn't touch me.
Oh, yeah.
Uh, now, Eddie, uh,
this, uh, police report says
that you were found with
Terry Maslin's gold Rolex watch
and several thousand dollars'
worth of his jewelry.
I don't steal.
The, uh, the current theory is
that, uh... Terry Maslin
caught you stealing his stuff,
and you killed him.
I don't steal,
and when I left he was alive.
Why'd you leave?
I had a good thing
going with the boy.
He was going to put
my name on a song,
and I could live
off the royalties,
but his mama didn't like me.
She didn't want me around.
I didn't want to
get her riled up,
so I figured I'd spend
the night in the park,
and then maybe I wouldn't have
to spend any more
nights in the park.
You know where I'm coming from?
Yeah, yeah.
Uh, who else knew
you were in the house?
Well, like I said,
his mama, his band,
and that girl I told
the police about.
She was there when I left.
The county police say
they have nothing to go on.
They, they, they don't know
who this girl is, her name.
They don't even
know if she exists.
Well, she does.
I might be a convicted felon,
but I didn't kill nobody.
Eddie, I believe you.
People of the state of
Georgia v. Edward Haynes.
Case number 245104.
Benjamin Matlock for
the defense, Your Honor.
Defendant is present
and waives further reading
of his rights in the indictment.
Pleads not guilty, requests
a jury trial, waives time.
How about, uh, April 12?
Fine.
Prosecution agrees.
As to the subject
of bail, Your Honor,
defendant has no
means of support,
no money.
When arrested, he was
found sleeping in a park
because, as he put it,
he could not afford a room.
Under the circumstances,
there's a real possibility
Mr. Haynes might
flee jurisdiction,
and I feel compelled
to recommend
the highest possible bail.
Uh, Your Honor, Eddie
"Cougar" Haynes' music
is in the Smithsonian Institute.
His music is in the
Library of Congress.
No compilation of the blues
would be complete without him.
He is a legend.
He is a national treasure.
Mr. Matlock, this
is all very true,
but it misses the point.
Your Honor, Eddie Haynes
is part of our cultural heritage.
Surely he deserves to be treated
with a modicum of respect.
Mr. Matlock, the man
has no money, no home.
If released, where
is he going to stay?
With me.
Fine.
Stay at my house.
Yeah, I said all right.
Defendant is released
on his own recognizance.
Court is recessed.
Well... there's no
furniture or chairs
or anything. Mm-mm,
there is none.
Terry Maslin liked it like this.
Odd.
Uh, Ben, this is Terry's
mother Lorraine Maslin.
Hello.
This is Ben Matlock.
I think I'll be outside.
Yes, um... I'm sorry
about your son.
Then why are you
defending his killer?
I don't think Eddie
Haynes killed anybody.
But he had my son's
things... His watch, his jewelry.
The, the diamond ring that
he had inherited from his father.
He loved that ring.
Why did he bring that
man back here with him?
If he hadn't done that,
he'd be alive today.
Um...
w-was, was there a
woman here that night?
I have no idea who was here.
Was Terry seeing
someone special?
There was a different
girl every week.
You had to have a
program to keep track.
Hmm.
Uh, I understand, uh, he had
a meeting with his old band.
They were all his friends.
They grew up together.
There was an argument?
They were like a family.
Sometimes families fight.
It doesn't mean anything.
Yes, ma'am.
Uh, thank you, Ms. Maslin,
and again, I'm very sorry.
♪ ♪
Nice.
Hey, man, I don't like nobody
coming up on me like that.
I'm sorry, I didn't
mean to surprise you.
That's all right.
Come on, sit down
and have a drink.
All right, uh, sure, sure.
You know, you said some
weird things about me in court.
Well, I just, I just meant
that you're a... fine artist.
Well, I sure appreciate that.
But I'm just a poor guit
picker from out of Mississippi.
My people all
worked in the fields.
Well, where'd you start singing?
In church.
I used to love
to sing in church.
See the tears coming
down people's face,
clapping their hands
and patting their feet.
You know you're
bringing joy to their hearts.
Oh, there's, there's
nobody that sings
and plays guitar the
way you do, Eddie.
Oh, thank you.
Um, I wonder if, uh...
if it'd be all right...
if I played with you a
little bit of something.
Well, I see you got a guitar.
That's a nice song.
Wait till it's finished.
If you're looking
for the gospel group,
they're in studio C.
Oh, thanks for
thinking I'd fit in.
Ben Matlock.
Oh, let me guess.
You'd like to ask
me a few questions.
Yes. Like "Why was the band
over at Terry's house
the day he was killed?"
Yeah. We were
there to discuss a tour.
Uh-huh.
Uh, was, uh... was
there an argument?
Down and out, man.
What about?
Keith wanted to
go out on the road,
and Terry didn't.
There's a lot of money in
those big rock and roll tours.
Millions.
And Terry didn't care?
Terry was as rich as Croesus.
He owned the publishing on our
music, so he didn't need a tour.
What about you?
What about me?
Did you need a tour,
Mr. Chiarro?
What I need is to turn
this album into a big hit.
If the tour had coincided
with the album's release,
it would have been perfect.
That's what I told Terry.
Well, you've been a big help.
Uh, uh, was there
a girl at the house
that day? I didn't see her.
Was Terry dating
anybody special?
Terry changed girls the
way he changed his shirts.
You know? Like, every day.
There's no way I'd
know who it was.
Oh, well... Thanks.
♪ ♪
Yes, I was angry.
I wanted a tour.
For the money?
Honey, do I look
like I need money?
Well... why?
I'm a drummer, and a
drummer needs a band.
I never thought about that.
We're usually not songwriters,
usually not singers.
When a band breaks
up, we go home.
I've been home for three years.
That's why I wanted a tour.
I want some fun.
I wanted something to do.
Why did your band,
Dreams, break up?
The party line on the break,
is "artistic differences."
And the truth?
The truth is, three years ago,
Paul Chiarro's wife left him.
Yeah?
She left Paul for his
oldest and dearest friend...
And business
partner, Terry Maslin.
Brianne Chiarro was an
airhead of the first order.
She actually thought she
could make Terry settle down.
It lasted three weeks,
and destroyed the band forever.
You met Paul?
Not yet.
Thanks.
I love Paul.
But Paul is
slightly obsessive...
uh, possessive and all
those good macho things.
He went berserk.
The band went to pieces.
And that, as they say, was that.
You think Paul killed Terry?
Sounds to me like you
think Paul killed Terry.
♪ ♪
What is he doing here?
You didn't say you were
going to bring him here!
We can't find the girl who
was here the other night.
And I thought if I could
bring Eddie back out here,
it might somehow jog
his memory. I want you to leave.
Ms. Maslin, the girl
might be our only
hope for clearing Eddie.
Please, this would only
take a few minutes, please?
Five minutes. Thank
you. Yes, ma'am.
Where was the girl?
Right over there, about
this high, dark hair,
good body.
What was she wearing?
Dungarees, tight, black
turtleneck sweater...
Come to think of
it, she didn't wear
that turtleneck when I left.
She had on a shirt, big shirt,
like it wasn't hers.
We got five minutes.
Boy's got enough clothes in
here to open up his own mall.
Not in here.
How about that?
Pay dirt.
Okay, let's see...
What do you think you're doing?
I never said you could
go upstairs. Yes, ma'am.
I never even said you
could come into the house!
And don't ever come back!
Ah. Well, back again.
Interesting place. Yeah.
No, you know what the problem is?
- What?
It's the same as always.
You're playing too loud.
Rock and roll. Hey! Gentlemen!
Hey, hey, hey! My new groupie.
Mr. Matlock, have you met
the rest of the band? No.
This is Keith Morrissey. Hello.
Dennis Johnson,
Ben Matlock. Yes, sir.
Hey. You're planning a tour?
Word gets around.
This should be the
biggest one ever.
A farewell memorial
tour, big auditoriums...
Major dollars,
Mr. Matlock. Yeah.
You get your way, Mr. Morrissey.
I guess so.
Did you want something?
Uh, well, I, I was hoping, uh...
we might talk. PAUL: Uh...
Well, we'll go inside.
Okay.
Good. Good, thanks.
All right.
What can I do for you,
Mr. Matlock? Well...
Uh, the other
members of the band
live in mansions.
You rent an apartment.
They drive big cars
and you're in a compact.
I'm broke.
Why is that?
Bad investments, bad habits.
Then you really
wanted that tour.
Right again.
Unless I miss my guess,
you were desperate
for that tour,
because you're a gambler.
I don't advertise my
problems, Mr. Matlock.
Terry was my friend.
He was the one
that bailed me out,
got me the help I
needed to stop gambling.
Well, that's honest.
I know how he felt about a tour.
There was no point
in arguing with him.
He'd made up his mind.
And you just accepted that?
Had no choice.
Thank you.
You've got to give Denny credit.
He's good. Yeah.
I understand you were
at Terry Maslin's the
night he was murdered.
And who, may I
ask, told you that?
Eddie Haynes
described you perfectly.
He says you can clear him.
I'm sorry. I wasn't there.
I've never been there.
Well, do you know
him? Ever met him?
No.
Then how did your sweater
get in his bedroom?
There must be a
million sweaters like that.
This one has your
laundry mark in it.
See? That's how I found you.
Look, I have no idea
how my sweater got there.
I only know that I
didn't put it there.
All right?
So, I'm leaving now.
Suzanne.
Look, if there's some reason
you can't tell me the truth,
maybe I can protect you.
What is it with you?
I am telling the truth.
I'll get a subpoena.
We'll see if they
believe you in court.
Excuse me.
♪ ♪
♪ How long? ♪
♪ Baby, how long ♪
♪ Has that evenin'
train been gone? ♪
♪ How long? ♪
♪ How long, baby, how long? ♪
♪ If I could holler ♪
♪ Like a mountain jack ♪
♪ Go up on the mountain ♪
♪ Call my baby back ♪
♪ Well, how long? ♪
♪ She been gone for so long ♪
♪ How long? ♪
♪ Baby, how long? ♪
♪ Ten dollar bill ♪
♪ Looks like a
window shade to me ♪
♪ 20 dollar bill, baby ♪
♪ Something I don't never see ♪
♪ I never see ♪
♪ Ain't seen one in so long ♪
♪ How long? ♪
♪ Baby, how long? ♪
♪ Lady, how long ♪
♪ How long ♪
♪ Has that evenin' ♪
♪ Train been gone? ♪
♪ How long? ♪
♪ How long, baby, how long? ♪
How long? How long?
Eddie, you ever think
about settling down?
No, Ben. I got the
itch, I got to move.
Don't you think sometimes
you're getting a little...
too old for that?
Yeah. I'm too
old for everything.
I'm 67 and on trial for murder.
And I know I'm too old for that.
♪ How long? ♪
♪ Was that evenin' ♪
♪ Train been gone? ♪
♪ That evenin'
train been gone? ♪
♪ How long? ♪
♪ How long, baby? ♪
♪ Baby, how long? ♪
♪ How long? How
long? How long? ♪
Hi. We're looking
for Gillian Burns.
That's me.
I'm Michelle Thomas.
This is Ben Matlock. Hi.
You room with Suzanne Cullen?
Uh-huh.
Uh... Oh.
Oh, this is her jacket.
We're trying to find her.
Lots of luck.
You know where she is?
Not exactly.
Uh, ma'am, I have
a subpoena here
in Suzanne Cullen's name,
and I have every
intention of serving it.
You've got a big problem.
Suzanne skipped
the country. What?
She went to Europe.
Europe?
She comes from a super rich,
straitlaced family.
She gets caught in the middle of
a rock and roll murder
trial, she'll get cut off.
So she was there?
Oh, yeah. She was there.
But she won't be
back for a couple years.
I pushed her too hard.
I'm sorry, I-I just
pushed her too hard.
♪ Who for me ♪
♪ My burden shares? ♪
♪ Oh, yes ♪
♪ None but thee ♪
♪ Dear Lord ♪
♪ And when ♪
♪ This feeble life is o'er ♪
♪ Time for me ♪
♪ Will be no more ♪
♪ Guide me gently ♪
♪ Safely home ♪
♪ To thy Kingdom's shore ♪
♪ To thy shore ♪
♪ Oh, just ♪
♪ A closer walk with thee ♪
♪ Grant it, Jesus ♪
♪ If you please ♪
♪ Daily walking ♪
♪ With thee ♪
♪ Let it be ♪
♪ Dear Lord ♪
♪ Let it be. ♪
Well...
I surely thought we
could find that girl and...
she would clear you.
Well...
I never have been big
in the breaks department.
Do I know that song?
I don't think so.
Sounds familiar.
That's the song Terry Maslin
was writing for me
when he got murdered.
Ain't nobody heard it but me.
No.
I've heard it, too.
Mr. Chiarro...
uh, how long had you
known Terry Maslin?
We went to high school together.
And-and when did you start
first playing in
a band together?
Around 1973.
Terry joined my band, Savannah.
Ah, and you continued
to play together?
Yeah. There were a lot
of bands around that time.
They'd come and go.
But one way or another,
Terry and I'd wind up together.
And-And-And you
were good friends?
That's right.
And then, in the late '70s, uh,
you all formed Dreams and became
very successful. That's right.
Did, did, did this enormous
success affect your friendship?
No, not at all.
Good, good.
Uh, you were married in 1983.
Yes. And Dreams was
at the peak of its success.
Just one million-selling
album after another.
I believe they're
called "platinum."
That's right. And
you had a, uh...
several singles and big tours.
And then, uh,
quite unexpectedly,
the band broke up in 1986.
Is that right? Yeah.
It was because of
your marriage, wasn't it?
In a manner of speaking.
Your wife left you for Terry,
didn't she? Yeah.
And you didn't want to
work with him anymore.
That's right.
Yeah, well...
But, but the...
the fact is that, uh,
you shared several
business investments with him,
and you couldn't
exactly break it off
like that, could you? Yeah.
We were like a
divorced couple with kids.
We couldn't get
rid of each other.
And then after a while,
the friendship came back.
Oh, that's good.
That's good.
Uh, what about the band?
Oh, the band never
recovered. No.
Well, I... that's why I guess
you went on what they
call a "solo career"?
Yes. In fact,
y-you're just finishing
recording your
second solo album.
And both your first
and second albums
have been recorded,
uh, at a studio
called Premiere Sound,
is that right? Yeah.
Is that where you
met Suzanne Cullen?
Suzanne who? Cullen.
I don't think I know
anyone by that name.
No? Uh, well... The police, uh,
the police took this jacket
from her apartment
uh, last night, and, uh...
In fact, I saw, uh, Gillian
Burns, her roommate,
wearing it at Premiere Sound.
See, it's got her name...
See, "Suzanne"...
Embroidered on the front.
And "Premiere
Sound" on the back.
Now, does seeing this
jacket, uh, jog your recollection
of Suzanne Cullen?
Okay, I knew her.
Okay.
In fact, you, uh, you
bought this jacket for her,
didn't you? Yes!
And you gave it to her
personally as a present...
Yes.
You were seeing
her, weren't you?
No!
Yes, you were.
And she threw
you over for Terry,
didn't she? No.
Second woman to
leave you for Terry,
how about it? That's a lie!
You're a big rock and roll star.
Nobody treats you like that.
Especially your
supposed friend, Terry.
You hated him.
Hated him, and you saw
this itinerant man in his house,
your new opportunity
was knocking.
You left with the band
when you were supposed to,
but you came back later.
And you murdered Terry Maslin,
and framed Eddie Haynes.
Your Honor, I object!
This is pure speculation.
It is not speculation,
Your Honor.
May I show you?
Overruled. Proceed.
Thank you. I believe
the first time we met
was at Studio B
at Premiere Sound.
And you were, you were writing
a new song for your
second solo album.
Is that right? Yes, I was.
Have you played
that song for anyone?
No.
Have you played it
outside the studio?
No. So no one in this courtroom
could've heard that song.
That's right.
Um... Mr. Chiarro...
Thank you.
I wonder if you would mind
just playing that
song for the court.
Your Honor?
Your Honor.
Go ahead.
Please play the
song, Mr. Chiarro.
Don't stop playing, it's pretty.
I don't remember any more.
Want me to go to Premiere
Sound and get the sheet music?
Mr. Chiarro?
Please play the
song, Mr. Chiarro.
How can my client
possibly know that song?
I don't know.
You said yourself you never
played it for anyone else.
How can he possibly know it?
I said I don't know.
It's because you
stole that song.
Eddie Haynes told the police
and he'll testify in this court,
that Terry Maslin
was writing him a song.
A song that would
provide him with royalties
for who knows how
long... Maybe a long time.
So you didn't write that
song you were playing.
Terry Maslin did.
And that's how Eddie
Haynes knows it.
Your problem is...
Terry hadn't started
writing that song
before you left the house
with the band the
day of the murder.
And the only possible way
you could even know of the song
is if you returned
later that night,
which you did.
You did.
And you killed Terry Maslin.
And you stole his
watch and his valuables
and the diamond ring
his father gave him.
And you found Eddie,
and planted them on him.
And before you left, you saw
the sheet music on the piano.
And you said, "What
the hell?" And you took it.
You needed a hit.
From what I hear,
your solo career
needs a shot in the arm.
You desperately needed a hit.
You stole that song.
Ambition.
We might never have
known, but ambition
got the better of you.
Nothing further.
Ladies and
gentlemen of the jury,
have you reached a verdict?
We find the defendant,
Edward Haynes, not guilty.
♪ Well, let the
Midnight Special ♪
♪ Shine your light on me ♪
♪ Well, let the
Midnight Special ♪
♪ Shine your
ever-loving light on me ♪
♪ Well, yonder come Miss Rosa ♪
♪ How in the world do I know? ♪
♪ Well, I know her by her
apron and the dress she wore ♪
♪ Umbrella on her shoulder ♪
♪ Piece of paper in her hand ♪
♪ Well she's gonna
see the governor ♪
♪ Just a decent man ♪
♪ Let the Midnight Special ♪
♪ Shine the light on me ♪
♪ Well, let the
Midnight Special ♪
♪ Shine your
ever-loving light on me ♪
♪ When you get
up in the morning ♪
♪ And the big bell rings ♪
♪ You go marching to the table ♪
♪ You find the same damn thing ♪
♪ No forks on the table ♪
♪ Ain't nothing in the pan ♪
♪ And if you say
anything about it ♪
♪ You'll have
trouble with the man ♪
♪ Let the Midnight Special ♪
♪ Shine the light on me ♪
♪ Well, let the
Midnight Special ♪
♪ Shine your
ever-loving light on me ♪
♪ Well if you ever go
to Houston, Texas ♪
♪ Oh, you better walk right ♪
♪ Well, you better
not squabble ♪
♪ And you better not fight ♪
♪ That cop will arrest you ♪
♪ He'll sure take you down ♪
♪ Well, you can bet
your bottom dollar ♪
♪ That you're jailhouse bound ♪
♪ Well, let the
Midnight Special ♪
♪ Shine the light on me ♪
♪ Well, let the
Midnight Special ♪
♪ Shine your
ever-loving light on ♪
♪ Ever-loving light on,
ever-loving light on me. ♪
www.tvsubtitles.net